<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf8"?>

<letters xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">

  <letter id="1">
  
    <image src="mums528-i001-001.png"/>
    <image src="mums528-i001-002.png"/>
  
    <title>
      Letter from Waldemar Schultze to Jennie Schultze
    </title>

    <creators>
      <name>
        Schultze, Waldemar
      </name>
    </creators>

   <!--The is no contributer information for this record -->
    <contributers>
      <name></name>
      <name></name>
    </contributers>

    <date>
      <day>30</day>
      <month>6</month>
      <year>1943</year>
    </date>

    <source>
      Special Collections and University Archives, W. E. B. Du Bois Library, University of Massachusetts Amherst.
    </source>

    <citation>
      Robert and Waldemar Schultze Papers (MS 528). Special Collections and University Archives W.E.B. Du Bois Library, University of Massachusetts Amherst.
    </citation>

    <letterOrigin>
      <location>Unites States Disciplinary Barracks</location> 
      <city>Fort Leavenworth</city>
      <state>Kansas</state>
      <zipCode></zipCode>
    </letterOrigin>

    <letterContent>
      <addressee>
        <location>875 Richmond Av.</location> 
        <city>Buffalo</city>
        <state>New York</state>
      </addressee>

      <letterBody>
        <p>
         Dear Mother,
        </p>
        <p>
          This is the first letter I have had an opportunity to write you since leaving Fort Jay, and I know you must be anxious to hear from me.
        </p>
        <p>
          Bob and I are both feeling as well as can be expected considering our present circumstances. We both have high blood pressure, mine has been 160/100 for the past 2 days, and Bob's 158/96, but my sinus infection has not caused me quite so much trouble since leaving N.Y. State. I believe the air is dryer here and is responsible for any alleviation that has taken place.
        </p>
        <p>
          While a prisoner here remains in their so-called 1st grade, he is able to write twice a week, in second grade once a week, and in third grade once a month. These grades refer to classifications that ostensibly are for conduct while here. It is quite possible to lose a conduct rating, as I understand it, by not having a perpetually rusting tin cup polished brightly for daily inspection, although the tin plating long ago disappeared and the cup is rusty again within 2 hours after wetting.
        </p>
        <p>
          The food here is good and is well-cooked, with one exception, the gravy, which is nothing but flour, water, and bacon grease, Strangely enough, however, no condiments, not even salt, are provided on the table, to the detriment of otherwise very good meals. While meat here is unrationed and is plentiful, toilet paper; believe it or not, is rationed. A 5¢ roll must last a prisoner 45 days, or else -- ? Perhaps, however, a prisoner can purchase additional if it should be necessary.
        </p>
        <p>
          Please see that my subscriptions are transferred here as soon as possible from Fort Jay.  Give Florence and Helen my regards, and thank Joe for his efforts in my behalf in managing my business.  Find out from Joe how tube deliveries are at the present time, first to satisfy my curiosity; and also let me know if you are receiving your remittance regularly from him. If he is not taking care of your support in accordance with the instructions I left him, I wish to know it, so I can write, and correct the matter.  You can tell Joe to subscribe to Electronics magazine for me and send it to this address direct from the publisher. He should also have a copy of Palmer's "Calculus for Home Study," sent me by the publisher, whose name he can obtain from Ulbrichs. In future letters I'll copy the "Prisoner's Handbook" issued here, and the contents of the detached letter form stub.
        </p>
        <p>
          Love, Waldemar
        </p>
      </letterBody>
    </letterContent>
  </letter>

  <letter id="2">

    <image src="mums539-i056-001.png"/>
  
    <title>
      Letter from Joe Verret to Thomas Barton
    </title>

    <creators>
      <name>
        Verret, Joe
      </name>
    </creators>

    <!-- No contributer data is currently present for this record -->
    <contributers>
      <name></name>
      <name></name>
    </contributers>

    <date>
      <day>26</day>
      <month>11</month>
      <year>1965</year>
    </date>

     <source>
        Special Collections and University Archives, W. E. B. Du Bois Library, University of Massachusetts Amherst.
    </source>

    <citation>
      Robert and Waldemar Schultze Papers (MS 528). Special Collections   and University Archives 
    </citation>

    <!-- The letter origin location is unknown -->
     <letterOrigin>
      <location></location> 
      <city></city>
      <state></state>
      <zipCode></zipCode>
    </letterOrigin>

 
    <letterContent>
      <addressee>
        <name>Tom Barton c/o ASOC</name>
        <location>1521 Port St.</location> 
        <city>New Orleans</city>
        <state>Louisiana</state>
        <zipCode>70177</zipCode>
      </addressee>

      <letterBody>
        <p>
         Dear Comrade Barton:
        </p>
        <p>
          I am happy to see that there is still some meaningful revolutionary spirit left within ASOC.  Your article on Cd. Raphael's pacifism was good.  But the fact that an uncertain pacifist element has been admitted into the ranks of those who are supposed to be revolutionary socialists disturbs me.  The matter of pacifism to my mind should be cleared up before anyone is allowed to join ASOC.  Good God -- you know it and so does anyone else with serious intentions of defeating the imperialists be accomplished on a world scale if we try tactics such as lying down in front of tanks of the bourgeoisie.  This element of pacifism will surely not strengthen our ranks but, will when crisis comes, weaken them.
        </p>
        <p>
          What kind of people compose the NAC who would make a statement as wishy-washy as the one on pacifism.  I could never seriously make an appeal outside of the student movement for anyone to join us with these elements present in our ranks.  I think that the NAC should reconsider the motion -- are we revolutionaries or are we just interested in having a nice sized organization.  Your article comrade Barton, in short, should be part of any mass propaganda which we us to attract revolutionary elements.  The working class will throw ASOC "on the dust heap of history" with these tactics. 
        </p>
        <p>
          If Cd. Raphael is un-educated in Marxism then educate him; if he is of the liberal-pacifist type that is currently leading the whole movement to defeat then throw him out.   I am in ASOC as a revolutionary -- that is why I left the SP not so I could just get away from the adult group.
        </p>
        <p>
          I have been working with the Deacons and I see the militancy that is coming out in the whole of the Southern movement.  The idea of these tactics on the part of the ASOC is one of the repulsive things that has yet to come out of ASOC.  I hope you will work to correct it.
        </p>
        <p>
          A Spartacist chapter has been set up down here since July and I have been working with them in various ways.  I asked for some information from the N.O. but received no answer.  So maybe you could help: What are our relations with the Independent Socialist Club?  Are we willing to work with certain Stalinist oriented groups(PL;M2M;WW)?  Also, could you send me some info on their unity with ACFI?
        </p>
        <p>
          Also, what is our position with respect to the NLF?  Have we completely repudiated them as a revolutionary group worthy of our support (and Russia's)? or are we supporting the mass movement of the working class and peasants of Vietnam even through they have a Stalinist leadership.
        </p>
        <p>
          Revolutionary greetings,
        </p>
        <p>
          Joe Verret
        </p>
      </letterBody>
    </letterContent>
  </letter>

  <letter id="3">

    <image src="mums563-i123-001.png"/>
    <image src="mums563-i123-002.png"/>
  
    <title>
      Message received clairaudiently by Mrs. Begg at Lake Pleasant, Fri. March 9, 1945.
    </title>

    <creators>
      <name>
        Memling, Charles (Spirit)
      </name>
    </creators>

    <contributers>
      <name>
        Begg, Dorothy
      </name>
      <name>
        Shattuck, Louise F.
      </name>
    </contributers>

    <date>
      <day>09</day>
      <month>03</month>
      <year>1945</year>
    </date>

    <source>
      Special Collections and University Archives, W. E. B. Du Bois   Library, University of Massachusetts Amherst.
    </source>

    <citation>
     Louise Shattuck Papers (MS 563). Special Collections and University Archives, W.E.B. Du Bois Library, University of Massachusetts Amherst     
    </citation>

    <!-- The letter origin location is unknown -->
     <letterOrigin>
      <location></location> 
      <city></city>
      <state></state>
      <zipCode></zipCode>
    </letterOrigin>

    <!-- The addressee information is incomplete for this record -->
    <letterContent>
      <addressee>
        <name>Mrs. Begg, and L.S.</name>
        <address>Lake Pleasant</address>
        <city></city>
        <state></state>
        <zipcode></zipcode>
      </addressee>

      <letterBody>
        <p>
         My dear Mrs. Begg, and L.S.  I address myself to you both in the most sincere and distressed apology for the unsettling and unhappy occurrences of the past several days.  It has been my extreme misfortune to have attracted to my person an imitator, and one of no mean powers!  He has succeeded, as you see, in making considerable mischief in my absence from the immediate presence of L.S..  I have been made aware of this interference, and have taken measures to prevent it, yet find my work in a fair way to be undone on my return each time.  I have taken the liberty of reading over the material L.S. has recorded and was much perturbed to find myself so erroneously represented.  I know little about the letter episode as it transpired, but on rigid questioning of the bogus Charles M. find he has long admired! our superior powers of prophecy and sought to emulate them! Making claims he could in no wise substantiate and otherwise disposting himself to his own great amusement.  This is altogether regrettable and I am deeply sorry that it has come about.  I should feel it was possible because of the newness of the instrument.  She has, naturally been eager to hear at all times, when, as a matter of fact, I have been present only with the work and the night we made the transition into sleep.  My sole instruction has been, and continues to be for the furtherance of L.S.'s great talent.  The lesser questions and answers are not in my province; hence the errors that have arisen.  No definite harm has been done, though the shaking of faith has been lamentable just now, when all was so new!  The more familiar medium would realize the vibratory force was totally different in our appearances!  How the trouble may be avoided in the future is of vital concern, and that no possible mishap could occur, I feel it wisest to limit my services to the creative sphere.  I am sure L.S. will agree to this as the wisest course to pursue, and be entirely willing to cooperate.  We have done some truly splendid work together, far more rapidly than I had thought possible at first.  I am greatly pleased at both her receptibility and accomplishment.  Error is a part of life in all it's phases, and that this has crept into our work is not too surprising.  We have to deal with thousands of spirits daily whose narrow earth-life has left them desirous of imitating some great personage when freed over here.  Usually the limitation is sincere admiration, undertaken with no malice aforethought!  Indeed, we encounter thousands of very sincere souls who insist they are Buddha or Christ or other avatars!  It takes careful guidance and great patience to show them the errors in conception, and before this is accomplished, many have succeeded in obtaining an "ear" or a "hand" back into earth channels.  Hence our occurrence is not, as I said, too surprising!  What makes our situation even more complicated is that this poor soul is also a very fine artist!  I shall do my best and as rapidly as possible eradicate this hindrance.  L.S. is a particularly sensitive and fine "machine" and I look for surpassingly fine results from our cooperation.  I want her to feel perfectly free to feel the resultant work is her own.  To no one, save those intimately concerned, as now, need she make any explanations as to the work, method, or result.  This figure, and those to come, is as much her creation as that of any artist in any line of art, for no one works unaided in the arts.  The only difference is that L.S. knows she is aided, and by whom!  (Very rare.)  To sum up (and I trust to clear up) all that has appeared under my name that was contradictory or false, was not of me, nor known of me.  "By their fruits shall ye know them." No Master could make either an error or a false statement.  Thus you can readily check out all that is not of me.  Do not be disturbed further by this.  Press on now to greater heights of achievement. While I have this sure way in, I should like to say further that errors often occur through the unconscious coloring by the mind of the recipient.  Thus the desired thing is often represented as occurring, or about to occur, even through the message as sent was the opposite.  Confusion is the dire result!  And despair!  But there are quagmires to overcome in every attempt in life.  Be not dismayed!  Do not believe, either, in any account of my personal life that may "come across" to you hereafter!  I shall send none.  Just a warning.  Most sincerely, CM.
        </p>
      </letterBody>
    </letterContent>
  </letter>
</letters>